残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気付くでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の天使 窓辺からやがて飛ぶたつ
ほとばしる熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
拡大なこう だけ食 opportunity
と思ったら
電流石を着るまで使った朝パラクターが 追いつから
たくさん置いて飲む池にも 判打にお飲み今日を
チョコココット湖で売り 終わり
さあなど あれに instal聚してやる
Oh, Commander Fuyutski. Good morning, sir.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Well, you're up early today, sir.
I've got to represent Commander Akari uptown.
Ah, today's the city council meeting, isn't it?
An exercise in ennui.
Akari always sticks me with the most boring and tedious assignments.
I couldn't handle it without the Magi's help.
Speaking of which, election day is coming up, isn't it?
Yes, but the council really has no authority anyway.
Actually, the Magi run just about everything.
Really? You mean the same three supercomputers we use?
Yes. Our government is run by the majority decision of three different computers.
I suppose it's a sort of a form of democracy.
And the council members just go along with their decisions?
Well, it's been an effective form of government thus far.
This city really is built on science.
We're so lucky to be living in such a wonderful time.
Eh, technophiles.
You're running an experiment with Unit Zero this morning, aren't you?
Yes. We're going to be performing the second prolonged Ava activation test at 10.30.
Huh. I'll expect good news.
Abort the test! Break the circuits!
Cutting circuits.
Power supply restored.
It seems that one's the problem again.
Yes. It looks like the conversion efficiency is 0.8% lower than our calculation.
The conversion is barely within tolerance, though. What'll we do?
Let's try it again using the same configuration,
but lower the reciprocal conversion rate by 0.01.
All right. Let's start the experiment over again.
Hey! Hold the elevator!
Got it.
Man, it's been a while since I ran that hard.
So, what's with the black expression, Sunshine?
It's nausea from having to see you.
Yes. Hold one minute, please.
What?
Uh...
Well...
Father...
Uh...
Well...
What is it? Hurry up!
Uh...
I'm supposed...
to tell my parents...
that an interview for
advanced
vocational education
is going to be
held at school.
I've delegated all of that to Katsuragi.
Don't bother me with such nonsense anymore.
Don't forward any more of these calls to me.
Huh?
The power's out?
No, it can't be.
It's not possible.
Something's wrong.
An accident?
Perhaps Dr. Akagi made a mistake, huh?
The main power supply is shut down.
Voltage level is zero.
Uh...
It's not our fault.
Well, what do you think?
The backup supply should switch back on any second now.
No, sir.
The backup circuits aren't working either.
That can't be.
Which circuits are still functioning?
Only 1.2% of them.
Only 9 circuits from number 2567.
Connect all the remaining power circuits
to maintain the Magi and Central Dogma.
But that could interfere with our life support systems.
Do it!
We need the Magi!
Nozomu Takahashi wants to help you
form a more cheerful government.
Man, that Captain Katsuragi sure is lazy.
I mean, can't she at least make the time
to go and pick up her own laundry?
Hmm.
Huh?
Maybe Commander Akari was just really busy.
I don't think so.
And it wasn't like he hung up.
It sounded more like the line had failed.
Hey, are you a man or what?
Why do you let each and every little incident
get under your skin?
What are you doing?
Here, let me...
Hmm?
Huh?
Stupid thing!
It must be broken, damn it!
What?
Right here!
We'd better head for the command center.
If the backup power hasn't kicked in yet...
Then something's very wrong.
What's the backup system?
There are three backup circuits.
It's impossible for all of these to fail at once.
Then that means...
These circuit breakers didn't go on their own.
Someone did this intentionally.
Well, it would be a disaster
if an angel were to attack right now.
Radar's detected an unidentified object.
Projected landing point is in the form of Atami region.
It must be angel number eight.
Yeah, an angel.
What'll we do?
I guess the standard procedure is to go full alert status.
It looks like this one's heading straight for Tokyo 3 and NERV.
Looks like it.
Well, there's nothing we can do.
It's still advancing.
Any word yet from Tokyo 3?
They're still not responding to our transmissions.
What in the hell are those NERV guys doing?
I never thought I'd actually have to use one of these escape tubes.
I figured they were just holdovers that we held onto just for our peace of mind.
Well, being prepared is half the battle.
This one doesn't work either.
None of the facilities work.
This is odd.
Has something happened in the geo front?
A natural assumption.
Well, let's try to contact NERV headquarters.
The emergency phone isn't working either.
There's no answer on line 77.
None of them work.
No, it's disconnected.
This one, too.
The main and emergency cables are all down.
So what now?
What are you looking for?
What do you think, Doomkopf?
I'm looking for my emergency manual.
We should go to NERV headquarters ourselves.
That's right.
But before that, we're going to have to decide which of us will be this group's leader.
Naturally, I have the best qualifications.
Any objections?
Well, let's go.
Nervous over this way.
We can use the access port for Route 7.
But the doors don't work.
Oh, we can open it manually.
Well, there you go, Shinji.
This is your department.
You're the one who wants to be in charge.
But whenever going gets tough, you always defer to me.
That damn council always defers to us when the going gets tough.
Well, what did they say?
Those Tokyo 2 buttheads, they're getting ready to flee, of course.
The angel is still advancing.
In any case, we've got to try and make contact with NERV.
But how are we going to do that?
We fly there ourselves.
This is the 3rd District JASDF.
An unidentified object is moving toward this area.
All residents must evacuate.
Oh, boy.
I got to report this to headquarters.
But how?
Oh, man.
Hey, vote for Takahashi.
He's the candidate who remains calm, even in situations like this.
Oh, right.
I'm dying.
It's too hot in here.
The air conditioners are down, too.
If you're so hot, Katsuraki, why don't you take off your shirt?
There's no reason for you to be shy, you know.
Don't even think about trying to take advantage of this situation.
Yeah, right.
It's getting even warmer now that the air is getting stagnant.
It's hard to believe that this base has the world's most advanced technology.
Yeah, but look at the commanders.
Even in this heat, they're both still cool and in command.
It's hot.
Yes.
Emergency vehicle passing through.
Hey, watch where you're driving.
Oh, my God.
It's a dead end.
Stop.
It's okay.
Ram this sucker.
This is an emergency.
To hell with the barriers.
This geofront was designed to be a self-sufficient colony.
It's supposed to be able to operate even when completely isolated from the outside.
It's impossible for all the power sources to have broken down.
Someone caused this?
It would be a logical way to indirectly dissect this facility.
You mean that they could figure out Nerve's layout by the restoration process?
They are clever bastards.
I could run a dummy program through the Magi.
That would make it more difficult to get a complete grasp of our structure.
Make it so.
Yes, sir.
I can't believe that the first havoc wrecked upon our headquarters was caused by another
member of our own species.
Mankind's greatest enemy is man himself.
This usually only takes two minutes.
Are you sure this is the right way?
Of course I'm sure.
We'll be at the geofront any minute now.
Uh, haven't I heard that four times already?
Jeez, why do you have to nitpick everything?
You're always so negative.
Me?
What?
Silence, please.
Oh, what now, Wonder Girl?
Listen.
Tension all nerd personnel.
There is an angel approaching.
It's Yuga!
Hey, Yuga!
Hey!
There's an angel approaching.
An angel is approaching.
A new angel?
We can't waste any more time.
There's a shortcut.
Hey, don't forget that I'm the leader here.
So, where is this shortcut?
This way may be quick, but we look really stupid.
Hey, just what are the angels?
Huh?
Why are you asking now?
Well, I don't know.
It just doesn't make sense.
Angels are messengers from God, right?
Why are we fighting angels?
What, are you stupid?
They attacked us.
When someone's attacking you, you can't just sit there and do nothing, right?
Let's see.
To the right.
I think the correct path is to the left.
Stop contradicting me.
Shinji, what do you think?
Uh, I'm not certain.
Look, I'm the leader, so you can both just shut up and follow me.
We're going up again.
I thought something was odd here.
So why didn't you say something earlier?
You're always nitpicking.
Huh?
This has got to be the geofront this time.
Well, we'd better hurry.
Now that I've visually confirmed the angels' presence...
There's an angel approaching.
We have to dispatch an EVA immediately.
But how?
Fyutski, take charge here.
What?
I'm going down to the cage to prepare the EVAs for manual launch.
Manually?
Can that be done?
We have a diesel generator for emergencies.
Well, yes, but...
Who is going to pilot them?
This way.
You're Commander Ikari's favorite, aren't you?
I guess that that means you get treated a little different, right?
Asuka, this isn't the time for this.
You always look so snug, too.
Hey, just because they like you best doesn't mean you can act so superior.
I don't act superior.
Hmm.
And I'm not treated any better, either.
I know that quite well.
Understood.
The termination plug has been ejected, sir.
Excellent.
Prepare for manual insertion of the entry plug.
But the pilots aren't here yet.
Don't worry.
They'll be along soon enough.
There's no way I can clear this away with my hands.
Then we will have to break into another ventilation duct in order to get there.
First child's feeling aggressive.
And I'll bet she'd do anything to stay number one.
Some people just think they're better than others.
Entry plug is fixed and ready.
Now all we need are the children.
If you dare look up my dress, I'll kill you.
Do you hear me, Shinji?
You look!
Prepare to eat!
No!
You!
I told you that the one.
What are you doing?
Huh?
Ah!
That's where you've been.
We've been waiting for you.
Prepare for manual entry.
Roger!
Lever open the hatches!
The Evas?
They're already on standby.
Huh?
But there's no power.
It was all done by hand.
The commander did it.
My father?
Commander Akari believed in you and prepared everything.
Ah!
All units activated using backup power supply.
Sever the primary hydraulic locks.
Rear!
Ah!
Hydraulic locks numbers 2 to 32 released.
Zero pressure.
The Evas are free, sir.
Understood.
Remove all of the remaining restraints and supports.
Commence launch.
Ah!
The angel has stopped directly above us!
Hurry up!
Get a move on!
The emergency batteries have been engaged!
Well, we're ready.
Let's move out!
Oh!
This is pathetic!
Vertical shaft inside.
Get out!
Oh!
No!
Wait!
I can't believe we're doing this!
It's so embarrassing!
Huh?
It's acid!
Watch out!
Huh?
Ah!
It would appear that the Angel plans to attack headquarters directly using that acid.
What do we do?
We're gonna beat it, of course.
Okay, but how?
We dropped our rifles and the battery packs on our backs are running out of power.
They will last more than another three minutes.
I've got an idea.
There will be three positions, defense, offense, and backup.
Defense's job will be to neutralize that Angel's AT field and to protect the offense from the acid bath.
Backup will go down the shaft, retrieve the rifles, and hand one to the offense, who will then fire a volley, destroying the target.
How does that sound?
I will take the defensive position.
Sorry, Wonder Girl.
That'll be my job.
But it's too dangerous.
That's why I'm doing it.
And don't forget I still owe you one from the last time we fought an Angel.
Shinji will be offense.
Rei will be the backup.
Got it?
Understood.
Right!
Here we go!
Ava, I'm charged!
Hey, Nami!
Asuka!
Get out of the way!
I'm clear!
Now we're even, Shinji.
Oh, no!
Please open!
Please!
Why won't it open?
I've got to go to the bathroom now!
Hey, you're not looking at my dress, are you?
No, ma'am.
Ah, watch out!
Ah!
Yes!
it's ironic without electricity and artificial light the sky can look so beautiful at night
yeah but without the lights it seems like there are no humans here
there i feel much more comfortable this way man fears the darkness and so he scrapes away at the
edges of it with fire philosophy huh so is that what makes mankind a special species is that why
the angels attack us what are you stupid who knows what they think
let me see where spring is like on jupiter and mars
in other worlds hold my hand in other worlds darling kiss me
feel my heart whistle and let me sing forevermore
you are all alone for all i want should adore
in other worlds
with his future
i love you
when misada was promoted to major shinji begins to learn about a personal vendetta against the angels
then it's up to the eva team to stop the largest and most dangerous angel yet
the size of this creature alone makes many abandon all hope
and that's before it unveils its terrifying new weapon
in